minitab.com 2019-09-28

# Privacy Policy | Minitab

Effective Date: 7/11/2019

Minitab, LLC ("Minitab" or "we") is committed to privacy and data protection. This Privacy Policy applies to all Personal Data Minitab collects from you (either an individual or a single entity acting on behalf of its authorized individual users), through our interactions with you and through our products; as well as how we use and protect that data. Minitab is the controller of this data.

The Privacy Policy applies to all websites which are run by, or under the control of, Minitab, LLC (collectively, the “Sites”), and our applications, products and services (including the Sites) (collectively, the "Services"). All references to “Minitab”, “the Company”, “we” and “our” include not only Minitab, LLC, located at 1829 Pine Hall Road, State College, PA, 16801-3210 USA, but also our wholly owned subsidiaries and affiliates, unless expressly stated otherwise.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the data you input to our Services, or the files generated using our Services (“Your Content”). You act as the controller of Your Content.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to any third-party applications or software that integrate with our Services, or any other third-party products, services or businesses (collectively, “Third Party Services”). Third Party Services are governed by their own privacy policies. We recommend you review the privacy policy governing any Third Party Services before using them.

Any questions or concerns regarding Minitab’s privacy and data protection practices can be directed to our Data Protection Officer at [dpo@minitab.com](mailto:dpo@minitab.com) or by calling +1-814-238-3280.

## Personal Data We Collect

Minitab collects data to provide the Services you request, ease your navigation on our Sites, communicate with you, and improve your experience using our Services. Some of this information is provided by you directly, such as when you create an account on our Sites, request a trial and/ or purchase a Service. Some of the information is collected through your interactions with our Services. We collect such data using technologies like cookies and other tracking technologies, error reports, and usage data collected when you interact with Minitab Services running on your device.

We also obtain data from third parties or use third parties to assist us with data collection. For example, we may supplement the data we collect as described in this section by purchasing demographic data from other companies. We also use services from other companies to help us determine a location based on your IP address notably to customize certain services to your location. In addition, we utilize third-party services to collect usage data.

The data we collect depends on the Services and features thereof that you use, and includes the following:

Name and contact data. We collect your first and last name, e-mail address, postal address, phone number, and other similar contact data. 

Credentials. We process passwords and related security information used for authentication and account access and information security purposes.

Payment data. We collect data necessary to process your payment if you make purchases, such as your payment instrument number (such as a credit card number).

Usage data. We collect personalized information about your use of our Services, to better understand uses thereof and identify potential improvements, as well as to send you promotional communications or offers tailored to your use of our Services. 

Examples include:

  * Information based on your use of our Services running on your device. This includes the types of files being imported, the types and frequency of tools and commands being used, the size and nature of projects, and the frequency and duration of use. Note that we do not collect any of the data that you input/use in our Services, only analytical data about how you use the Service.
  * Information on the web pages you visit on and off our Sites and the search terms you enter on our Sites.
  * Information regarding the performance of our Services and any problems you may experience while using them. This information enables us to diagnose problems and offer support in resolution.
  * Data about your device and the network you use to connect to our Services, including IP address, device identifiers, and regional and language settings.

Web requests. For our cloud-based Services, we collect information regarding every web request sent to the relevant servers. This information is used to provide support, as well as to assess usage and performance of our Services. The data collected for each request can include such things as timestamps, any exception messages, user agent, IP address, e-mail address, request time and duration, as well as files names. Note that we do not collect your project file data.

Location data. We collect your IP address and infer location such as city or postcode therefrom, when necessary in order to provide you with the Services or to send you promotional communications or for customer relationship management purposes.

Content. We may collect the content of messages you send to us, such as feedback or questions you ask our technical support representatives, when necessary to provide you with the Services you use. We will collect and utilize any data files you send to us for troubleshooting and improving our Services so long as you have anonymized, scrubbed, or deleted any personally identifiable information contained therein which you do not want us to collect or utilize. When you contact us, phone conversations or chat sessions with our representatives may be monitored and recorded in order to improve our services, facilitate the processing and resolution of your request or complaint. 

Surveys and Studies. We may ask you to participate in a survey or study; and may request information from you. Participation is voluntary, and you have the choice of whether to disclose any requested information.

## How We Use Personal Data

Minitab uses information that we collect from customers and visitors for the purposes of:

  * providing our Services;
  * providing ongoing support;
  * communicating with you, including promotional communications and customer relationship management (“CRM”);
  * providing information about other Services;
  * helping us run our company, for example to improve our Services or our security, train staff or perform marketing activities, including CRM; 
  * complying with our legal obligations and enforcing our legal rights, including the authorized use of our licenses; and
  * accounting and other administrative purposes.

Examples of the uses of information include:

Providing Services. We use data to carry out your transactions with us and to provide Services to you. Often, this includes personal data such as e-mail, name and address.

  * Customer support. We use data to diagnose and address problems and provide other customer and support services.
  * Activation. We use data, including device and application type, location, and unique device, application, network and subscription identifiers to activate software and devices that require activation.
  * Software Updates. Unless you have disabled the functionality of our Software Update Manager, our Services periodically communicate with our servers to perform functions such as checking for updates.

Improving Services. We use data to continually improve our Services, including adding new features or capabilities. Data is collected throughout your interactions with our Services that enable us to understand customer usage and tailor future capabilities.

We track general, non-personalized information (e.g., operating system, browser version and type of device being used) to know how many people visit specific pages of our Sites or utilize specific areas of our Services so that we may improve those Services. We may use your IP address to customize services to your location, such as the language displayed on our Sites.

Our Cookies Policy explains how we use cookies and similar technologies to collect information about the way you use our Services, and how to control them.

Please note that we use IP addresses on a highly restrictive basis to analyze trends, to administer the Sites, and to collect general information for aggregate use. 

Service Communications. We use data we collect to deliver and personalize our communications with you. For example, we may contact you by e-mail or other means to notify you of changes in information and updates to our Services or to our Privacy Policy. 

Marketing and event communication: We use Personal Data to deliver marketing and event communications to you across various platforms, such as e-mail, direct mail, social media, and online via our Sites. We also may send you invitations to trade shows or trainings relating to our Services that occur nearby you, based on your address.

Third parties may also market to you on our behalf based on your use of their third-party services. For example, some tradeshow organizers may collect precise geo-location (latitude and longitude) data when you grant permission through your mobile device’s system settings. Once you give permission, the tradeshow organizer may use your mobile device’s GPS, Bluetooth or Wi-Fi connections to serve geo-targeted information about Minitab, such as booth location. You should consult and review the relevant third-party privacy statement or policy for information on their data processing practices.

If we send you a marketing e-mail, it will include instructions on how to opt out of receiving these e-mails in the future. We also maintain e-mail preference centers for you to manage your information and marketing preferences. For information about managing e-mail subscriptions and promotional communications, please visit the Your Rights Regarding Personal Data section of this privacy statement. Please remember that even if you opt out of receiving marketing e-mails, we may still send you important Service information related to your accounts and subscriptions.

## How We Share Personal Data

It is the policy of Minitab and our wholly owned subsidiaries and affiliates to protect Personal Data both online and off-line. Access to Personal Data is restricted to only those employees or agents, contractors or subcontractors of Minitab who have valid reasons to access this information to perform any service you have requested or authorized, or for any other purpose described in this Privacy Policy. The information you provide will not be sold or rented to third parties.

We may provide your Personal Data to:

  * Minitab-controlled affiliates and subsidiaries, located in and outside your country, including outside the European Union (in such case, we will use appropriate legal framework to operate data transfers);
  * outsourced service providers who perform functions on our behalf, located inside or outside of the European Union (in such case, we will use appropriate legal framework to operate data transfers). For example, when you provide payment data to make a purchase, we will share payment data with banks and other entities that process payment transactions or provide other financial services, and for fraud prevention and credit risk reduction;
  * our authorized agents and representatives, located inside or outside of the European Union (in such case, we will use appropriate legal framework to operate data transfers), who sell products or provide services on our behalf, such as training service providers or product resellers;
  * anyone expressly authorized by you to receive your Personal Data;
  * anyone to whom we are required by law to disclose Personal Data, upon valid and enforceable request thereof.

Finally, we will access, disclose and preserve Personal Data, including your Content, when we have a good faith belief that doing so is necessary to:

  1. comply with applicable law or respond to valid legal processes, including from law enforcement or other government agencies, upon valid and enforceable request thereof; or
  2. operate and maintain the security of our Services, including to prevent or stop an attack on our computer systems or networks.

Please note that some of our Services may direct you to services of third parties whose privacy practices differ from Minitab’s. If you provide Personal Data to any of those services, your data is governed by their privacy statements or policies. Minitab, LLC and our wholly owned subsidiaries and affiliates are not responsible for the privacy practices of these other sites. Please review the privacy policies for these web sites to understand how they process your information.

We require third parties to only use your Personal Data for the specific purpose for which it was given to us and to protect the privacy of your Personal Data. We will only disclose your personal data to third parties who agree to keep your information confidential. 

## Handling of Personal Data

### Security of Personal Data

Minitab is committed to protecting the security of your Personal Data. Depending on the circumstances, we may hold your Personal Data in hard copy and/or electronic form. For each medium, we use technologies and procedures to protect Personal Data. We review our strategies and update as necessary to meet our business needs, changes in technology, and regulatory requirements.

These measures include, but are not limited to, technical and organizational security policies and procedures, security controls and employee training.

### Storage and Transfer of Personal Data

Personal Data collected by Minitab may be stored and processed in your region, in the United States or in any other country where Minitab, its affiliates or contractors maintain facilities, including outside the European Union. We take steps to ensure that the data we collect under this Privacy Policy is processed pursuant to the terms thereof and the requirements of applicable law wherever the data is located.

Minitab also collaborates with third parties such as cloud hosting services and suppliers located around the world to serve the needs of our business, workforce, and customers. In some cases, we may need to disclose or transfer your Personal Data within Minitab or to third parties in areas outside of your home country. When we do so, we take steps to ensure that Personal Data is processed, secured, and transferred according to applicable law.

If you would like to know more about our data transfer practices, please contact our Data Protection Officer at [dpo@minitab.com](mailto:dpo@minitab.com).

### Retention of Personal Data

Minitab retains Personal Data for as long as necessary to provide the Services and fulfill the transactions you have requested, or for other business purposes such as complying with our legal obligations, resolving disputes, and enforcing our agreements. We are required by law to keep some types of information for certain periods of time (e.g. statute of limitations). If your Personal Data is no longer necessary for the legal or business purposes for which it is processed, we will generally destroy or anonymize that information.

## Your Rights Regarding Your Personal Data

Minitab respects your right to access and control your Personal Data. You have choices about the data we collect. When you are asked to provide Personal Data that is not necessary for the purposes of providing you with our Services, you may decline. However, if you choose not to provide data that is necessary to provide a Service, you may not have access to certain features or Services.

We aim to keep all Personal Data that we hold accurate, complete and up-to-date. While we will use our best efforts to do so, we encourage you to tell us if you change your contact details and this can be easily accomplished using the [Manage Account](https://licensing.minitab.com/account/manage/) section. However, if you believe that the information we hold about you is incorrect, incomplete or out-of-date, please contact [dpo@minitab.com](mailto:dpo@minitab.com) or call +1-814-238-3280.

Access to Personal Data: In some jurisdictions, you have the right to request access to your Personal Data. In these cases, we will comply, subject to any relevant legal requirements and exemptions, including identity verification procedures. Before providing data to you, we will ask for proof of identity and sufficient information about your interaction with us so that we can locate any relevant data. We may also charge you a fee for providing you with a copy of your data (except where this is not permissible under applicable law).

If you are a corporate or institutional user of our Services (which means your employer or institution is a Minitab customer of such Services), please first request access to your Personal Data with your employer or institution. Your employer or institution will then be in touch with us with respect to your request. 

Correction and deletion: In some jurisdictions, you have the right to correct or amend your Personal Data if it is inaccurate or requires updating. You may also have the right to request deletion of your Personal Data. Please note that such a request could be refused because your Personal Data is required to provide you with the Services you requested, e.g. to deliver a Service or send an invoice to your e-mail address, or that it is required by the applicable law.

Portability: If you reside within the European Union, you have the right to ask for a copy of your Personal Data and/or ask for it to be ported to another provider of your choice. Please note that such a request could be limited to Personal Data you provided us with or that we hold at that given time and subject to any relevant legal requirements and exemptions, including identity verification procedures.

If you are a corporate or institutional user of our Services (which means your employer or institution is a Minitab customer of such Services), please first request access to your Personal Data with your employer or institution. Your employer or institution will then be in touch with us with respect to your request. 

Marketing preferences: If you have provided us with your contact information, we may, subject to any applicable Spam Act or similar regulation, contact you via e-mail, postal mail or telephone about Minitab products, services and events that may be of interest to you, including our newsletter.

E-mail communications you receive from Minitab will generally provide an unsubscribe link allowing you to opt-out of receiving future e-mail or to change your contact preferences. E-mail communications may also include a link to directly update and manage your marketing preferences. If you have a web account with Minitab, you can also change your contact preferences through the [Manage Account](https://licensing.minitab.com/account/manage/) section of our website. Please remember that even if you opt out of receiving marketing e-mails, we may still send you important Service information related to your accounts and subscriptions.

You can also request changes to your account by contacting Minitab via e-mail, postal mail, telephone or fax at the appropriate location found at: <http://www.minitab.com/contact-us/> or by e-mailing [unsubscribe@minitab.com](mailto:unsubscribe@minitab.com).

## Cookies & Similar Technologies

Minitab uses cookies (small, often encrypted, text files that are stored on your computer or mobile device) and similar technologies (“cookies”) to provide our Services and help collect data. This Cookies Policy explains how we use cookies to collect information about the way you use our Services, and how you can control them.

### How We Use Cookies

We use cookies to track how you use our Services by providing usage statistics. Cookies are also used to deliver Company information (including updates) and allow Service authentication to you based upon your browsing history and previous visits to the Sites. Information supplied to us using cookies helps us to provide a better online experience to our visitors and users and send marketing communications to them, as the case may be. Information supplied to us upon launching of our Services will enable Minitab to manage your permissions, license, license type, and improve the functionality of the Service.

While this information on its own may not constitute your “Personal Data”, we may combine the information we collect via cookies with Personal Data that we have collected from you to learn more about how you use our Services to improve them.

### Types of Cookies

We use both session cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent cookies (which stay on your device until you delete them). To make it easier for you to understand why we need them, the cookies we use with our Services can be grouped into the following categories:

  * Strictly Necessary: These cookies are necessary for the Services to work properly. They include any essential authentication and authorization cookies for our Services.
  * Functionality: These cookies enable technical performance and allow us to “remember” the choices you make while browsing our Sites, including any preferences you set. They also include sign-in and authentication cookies and IDs that enable you to return without additional sign-in.
  * Performance/Analytical: These cookies allow us to collect certain information about how you navigate the Sites or utilize the Services running on your device. They help us understand which areas you use and what we can do to improve them.
  * Targeting: These cookies are used to deliver relevant information related to our Services to an identified machine or other device (not a named or otherwise identifiable person) which has previously been used to visit our Sites. Some of these types of cookies on our Sites are operated by third parties with our permission and are used to identify advertising sources that are effectively driving customers to our sites.

Here is a representative list of the cookies we use.

### Cookies Set by Third Party Sites

To enhance our content and to deliver a better online experience for our users, we sometimes embed images and videos from other websites on the Sites. We currently use, and may in future use content from sites such as Facebook, LinkedIn and Twitter. You may be presented with cookies from these third-party websites. Please note that we do not control these cookies. The privacy practices of these third parties will be governed by the parties’ own privacy statements or policies. We are not responsible for the security or privacy of any information collected by these third parties, using cookies or other means. You should consult and review the relevant third-party privacy statement or policy for information on how these cookies are used and how you can control them.

### Social Sharing

We also embed social sharing icons throughout our Sites. These sharing options are designed to enable users to easily share content from our Sites with their friends using a variety of different social networks. If you choose to connect using a social networking or similar service, we may receive and store authentication information from that service to enable you to log in and other information that you may choose to share when you connect with these services. These services may collect information such as the web pages you visited and IP addresses, and may set cookies to enable features to function properly. We are not responsible for the security or privacy of any information collected by these third parties. You should review the privacy statements or policies applicable to the third-party services you connect to, use, or access. If you do not want your Personal Data shared with your social media account provider or other users of the social media service, please do not connect your social media account with your account for the Services and do not participate in social sharing on the Services.

### Other Similar Technologies

Minitab web pages may use other technologies such as web beacons to help deliver cookies on our Sites and count users who have visited those Sites. We also may include web beacons in our promotional e-mail messages or newsletters to determine whether you open and act on them as well as for statistical purposes.

In addition to standard cookies and web beacons, our Services can also use other similar technologies to store and read data files on your computer. This is typically done to maintain your preferences or to improve speed and performance by storing certain files locally.

### How to Control and Delete Cookies

Cookies can be controlled, blocked or restricted through your web browser settings. Information on how to do this can be found within the Help section of your browser. All cookies are browser specific. Therefore, if you use multiple browsers or devices to access websites, you will need to manage your cookie preferences across these environments.

If you are using a mobile device to access the Sites, you will need to refer to your instruction manual or other help/settings resource to find out how you can control cookies on your device.

Please note: If you restrict, disable or block any or all cookies from your web browser or mobile or other device, the Sites may not operate properly, and you may not have access to our Services available through the Sites. Minitab shall not be liable for any impossibility to use the Sites and Services or degraded functioning thereof, where such are caused by your settings and choices regarding cookies. 

### Do-Not-Track Disclosures

We do not support "Do Not Track" browser settings and do not currently participate in any Do Not Track frameworks that would allow us to respond to signals or other mechanisms from you regarding the collection of your personal information.

OUR SITES ARE NOT INTENDED FOR CHILDREN

The Services are not directed to or intended for use by children under the age of 16. Consistent with the requirements of the U.S. Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, if we learn that we received any information directly from a child under age 13 without his or her parent’s verified consent, we will use that information only to inform the child (or his or her parent or legal guardian) that he or she cannot use the Sites or Services.

If you are a California resident who is under age 18 and you are unable to remove publicly-available content that you have submitted to us, you may request removal by contacting us at the address specified below in the “Questions or Complaints Handling” section of this Privacy Policy. When requesting removal, you must be specific about the information you want removed and provide us with specific information, such as the URL for each page where the information is located, so that we can find it. We are not required to remove any content or information that: (1) federal or state law requires us or a third party to maintain; (2) was not posted by you; (3) is anonymized so that you cannot be identified; (4) you don’t follow our instructions for removing or requesting removal; or (5) you received compensation or other consideration for providing the content or information. REMOVAL OF YOUR CONTENT OR INFORMATION FROM THE SITE DOES NOT ENSURE COMPLETE OR COMPREHENSIVE REMOVAL OF THAT CONTENT OR INFORMATION FROM OUR SYSTEMS OR THE SYSTEMS OF OUR SERVICE PROVIDERS. We are not required to delete the content or information posted by you; our obligations under California law are satisfied so long as we anonymize the content or information or render it invisible to other users and the public.

## EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks

Minitab participates in the EU-U.S. and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks. Please see our Privacy Shield Policy for information about Minitab’s data practices regarding personal information it receives from European Union member countries and Switzerland pursuant to the respective Privacy Shield frameworks. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program generally, and to view Minitab’s certification, please visit [ https://www.privacyshield.gov/](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

## Notice to Users Outside the United States

Minitab is headquartered in the United States. Your use of our Services is governed by United States law. If you are using the website from outside of the United States, your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States where Minitab’s servers are located. In accordance with and as permitted by applicable law and regulations, we reserve the right to transfer your information, process, and store it outside your country of residence to wherever we or our third-party service providers operate.

## Questions or Complaints Handling

We understand that you may have questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices or may wish to file a complaint. In such case, please contact us in one of the following ways:

Minitab Data Protection Officer

E-mail: [dpo@minitab.com](mailto:dpo@minitab.com)

Phone: +1-814-238-3280

Mail: Attention: Data Protection Officer

Minitab, LLC

1829 Pine Hall Road

State College, PA 16801 USA

If you are not satisfied with our answer or how Minitab manages your Personal Data, you may also have the right to make a complaint to a data protection regulator. If you reside within the European Union, a list of National Data Protection Authorities can be found here: <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm>.

If you reside in Australia, you may obtain information about privacy and lodging a complaint with the Federal Privacy Commissioner (FPC) at [www.oaic.gov.au](http://www.oaic.gov.au/)

## Changes To This Privacy Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy based upon evolving laws, regulations and industry standards, or as we may make changes to our business including our Services. We will post changes to our Privacy Policy on this page and encourage you to review our Privacy Policy when you use our Services to stay informed. If we make changes that materially alter your privacy rights, Minitab will provide additional notice, such as via e-mail or through the Sites or other Services. If you disagree with the changes to this Privacy Policy, you should discontinue your use of the Services. You may also request access and control of your Personal Data as outlined in the Your Rights Regarding Personal Data section of this Privacy Policy.
